That’s weird.
♪ Here we are going far ♪
♪ to save all that we love ♪
♪ If we give all we've got ♪
♪ we will make it through ♪
♪ Here we are like a star ♪
♪ shining bright on your world today ♪
♪ Make evil go away ♪
♪ Code Lyoko we'll withstand it all ♪
♪ Code Lyoko be there when you call ♪
♪ Code Lyoko we will stand real tall ♪
♪ Code Lyoko stronger after all ♪
Aelita, hurry!
Yumi’s only got 10 life points left!
Get ready, girls.
I’m starting up the devirtualization process.
Activated towers, Lyoko battles, danger.
Aren’t you guys startin'
to get sick of all this?
No.
Well, sometimes I really wish
we were done with XANA.
Uh, you missed an episode, Ulrich.
Remember, Aelita's
carrying a miserable virus
that links her to her old friend XANA.
Bye-bye XANA means bye-bye Aelita.
And I don’t know how to
create an anti-virus.
I mean, not just yet.
Hey, I have an idea!
Why don't we explore the new
mysterious sector we discovered?
Sector five?
But we don’t know what’s in it!
Sure we do!
There are monsters,
ultra-dangerous traps,
and a scyphozoa, as you call it,
that wants to steal Aelita’s memory.
You’re right, but what if
there's something else there?
Like information about XANA?
We have to go back.
Good idea.
All three of us will go.
You mean all four of us.
I want to be part of this expedition.
With that scyphozoa slinking around?
No way.
What if there’s a tower to deactivate?
Think about it!
I have to be there.
Come on, Einstein!
With bodyguards like us,
she has nothing to worry about!
And I promise to be careful!
Okay.
Tomorrow night, exploration.
(GASPS)
Oh my gosh! It’s so late!
My parents must be
going bananas!
Bye! See you tomorrow!
And as for us, we missed dinner again.
And when I think it was
spaghetti and meatballs!
Yumi, we need to talk.
You come home late
every single night.
Tonight is the last straw.
It’s past 10 o’clock
and you didn't even bother
to telephone us.
And you haven’t eaten anything, either.
What’s going on, dear?
If you have a problem,
you know you can tell us.
No, really. Everything’s fine.
I was studying math at Maïtena’s house.
I told you already.
Maïtena Lecuyer?
Uh-huh.
Hmm. That’s strange.
When I called her, she was studying.
By herself.
You’re lying to us, Yumi.
That’s not like you.
What’s the matter with you?
I worry about you, sweetheart.
Tell me what’s bothering you.
I promise you that
everything's just fine.
You saw my last report card.
It was great, so why worry about me?
(SIGHS)
I’m concerned, Takeo.
We’re going to have to
get a lot more strict.
It’s nice of you to come with me,
but I’m big enough to go
to school alone. Really, I am.
You are, huh?
If you were, then you’d stop lying to us
and tell us why you come
home so late all the time.
Are you gonna watch me
24 hours a day? Is that it?
Am I in prison or something?
We’re trying to understand you
and to protect you, too.
Oh, wow!
The entire Ishiyama family!
I bet that you’ll be
picking me up as well, huh?
I'll be waiting for you
here at 5 o'clock.
I advise you not to be late.
Oh, isn’t that adorable!
(CACKLES)
They’re not gonna ease up on me.
Oh, what a mess.
The worst thing is
I hate lying to them.
Just explain to them that
we’re fighting in a virtual universe
against a demonic
artificial intelligence.
That ought to reassure them.
Dork.
You’ve got to win back
their trust in you.
I think maybe you should
stay away from Lyoko for a little while.
Huh?
What about exploring sector five!
It’s for tonight, isn’t it?
Don’t worry. Jeremie will
give you a play-by-play update.
Promise.
(SCHOOL BELL RINGS)
Come on, guys.
I know you’re all dying to go
to Mrs. Hertz's class. Off we go.
Did you study for the
marine biology test?
Of course I did! Listen.
Fish are remarkably
well adapted to water.
What’s more, they can swim.
You are so lame.
(LAUGHTER)
Off to the forest sector!
Transfer Ulrich.
Transfer Odd.
Transfer Aelita.
Scanner Ulrich.
Scanner Aelita.
Scanner Odd.
Virtualization!
Everything okay?
We’re good.
The monsters must be sleeping.
They need all the sleep
they can get to recover from
all the grief we’ve been giving them.
You have to get to the
other end of the sector
to take the transporter.
I’m going to materialize your rides.
Yahoo!
Yeah!
Odd, you promised to be careful!
No problem!
Go straight ahead and hurry up
before the monsters get there!
We made it, Jeremie!
Okay. I’m entering the code.
Scipio.
There’s the transporter.
Whoa.
Are you there, Jeremie?
Yumi?
Everything okay?
Yumi!
Yeah, they’re in the transporter.
All is well.
Tell them I’m thinking about them.
Happy campers?
Yep. I’m beginning to get
used to these little trips.
Ugh, not me!
I shouldn’t have had
that fifth dessert at lunch.
Jeremie, the wall's about to open.
Right. Meaning the
countdown's gonna start.
You’ve got to find a
way to deactivate it.
That must be the answer
to exploring further.
Watch it, guys!
Everything will be fine.
Odd promised to be careful.
It started!
You know what'll happen if Aelita
loses her life points, don't you!
Don’t worry.
We have no intention of losing her.
The last time, there was a big room
at the end of this hallway.
I've got a feeling the
architecture of the core zone
changes each time you go there.
That’s a great help
for finding our way around.
If we knew everything,
we wouldn’t be exploring.
Come on. Let’s go!
Look out! You've got
two creepers on your tail!
Laser arrow!
You’ve only got three minutes
left to stop the countdown! Get going!
That way.
Come on!
Haven’t we already
been through here?
How should I know?
Everything looks
the same in this place!
This way!
Wow, 40 life points in one go!
Those creepers sure are powerful!
They’re powerful!
And really ugly, too!
Jeremie, any ideas?
No, but I got news for you.
You’re in a labyrinth.
Make a left at each fork,
and leave a mark there.
If the way is already marked,
then make a right.
This is incredible!
We’ll never get out of this thing!
You’d better!
Just two minutes left to find
a way to stop the countdown!
We’re out, Jeremie! We made it!
Nothing like having
a little luck on your side.
Hey, Einstein, why
complicate things, huh?
Ah, great. Now what do we do?
Jeremie, can you see
anything from your end?
So, you need me again, huh?
Go back to where you were.
I spotted a mechanism on the wall.
Hurry! Time's running out!
There!
Let me at it!
Fourteen! Thirteen! Twelve!
Eleven! Ten! Nine!
Eight! Seven! Six!
Five! Four!
Agh!
No!
Ulrich!
Aelita, the countdown is over.
The room is bound to change now.
You okay?
Well, no more creepers. That’s a start.
Don’t worry.
I’ll rematerialize Odd and Ulrich,
and I’ll get you out of there.
Come on, come on!
(BEEPS)
Oh, no!
Aelita, Odd and Ulrich
didn’t come back!
What?
But that’s impossible. Are they lost?
For the moment, they are.
So there’s no rematerialization
from sector five?
Sure there is.
Once we find the right program.
And do you think you can find it?
It’s probably as easy as
finding your antivirus.
But don’t worry.
I'm gonna do the impossible.
Hiroki, could you make
some more noise, please?
Sorry, Yumi. The volume's
as high as it goes.
Hiroki.
Go into the other room, Hiroki.
Go on now.
I pass.
Me, too. I pass.
Then the game is over!
(LAUGHS)
I have five points more than you!
On the Goban, yes.
Don’t forget that I played the whites.
With Komi, I win by half a point.
Oh.
(YAWNS)
Well, it’s bed time.
Goodnight.
Goodnight, my dear.
Jeremie, how’s it going?
Badly. Head for the factory.
Jeremie?
Can you hear that?
It’s the scyphozoa!
It’s heading towards you!
Stay calm. Yumi’s coming.
(SCREECHING)
Yumi, can I come in?
I want to talk to you for a minute.
Huh?
Yumi?
Jeremie, I’m in the elevator.
You have to get Aelita in sector five!
The Scyphozoa is there!
What about Odd and Ulrich?
You want the best case scenario?
I’d rather.
I’ve got about a one in a million
chance of finding the right code
to bring them back.
(YAWNS)
So sorry to bother you at such
a late hour, Headmaster Delmas,
but we’re very worried.
Yes, yes. I understand.
But it’s quite possible
that Yumi is somewhere on the campus.
Why, sure!
She’s probably hanging out
with her little gang of friends.
Come on.
You’re on the edge of the territory, Yumi.
Better be careful.
XANA’s going to do all that he can
to keep you from taking the transporter.
Jeremie! Enter…the code!
Yumi?
Huh. No one’s here.
No one’s in Stern’s room either.
Looking for someone?
Uh, Sissi. Would you
know where your friends
Stern, Belpois, and
Della Robbia might be?
Probably up to no good. As usual.
But I don’t know where.
Although, their little mascot
can find them for you.
Mascot? What mascot?
Tada!
A flea-bitten mangy mutt!
Huh. Well, excuse me, Mr. Delmas.
Ew. Hey, little puppy.
Where’s your master, huh?
Go get him!
(YAPS)
Let’s follow him!
Hang in there, Aelita.
Yumi’s on the way.
I hope so.
Yumi? Can you hear me?
Yes. I’m in the arena.
The transporter got to me just in time.
Horrible Kankrelat.
Listen up, now.
You have to get to the corridor
and trigger the mechanism
before the countdown runs out, okay?
Okay.
If I’m right about how
the core zone functions,
my plan should work.
Huh. What’s the matter with that hound?
Oh, I don’t believe it!
This reminds me of when I
used to work in the sewers.
You, uh, used to work in the sewers, Jim?
I, uh…I’d rather not talk about it.
Only two minutes left, Yumi!
Down to 10 points, Yumi!
This is not the time to mess up!
(BARKS
(SQUEALS)
Jim, we’re wasting time!
Will you let go of that slipper! You flea-bitten--
Come on! Let go of it!
Yumi, this is no time to drag your feet.
I’ve located the mechanism.
It’s on your right.
You have ten seconds!
Two seconds!
It works, Jeremie!
The whole zone is being reconfigured!
We did it!
Aelita, take the access behind you!
Huh?
Wow!
It’s some kind of elevator!
You know what we do
with elevators, right?
We ride 'em!
Yumi!
Try to grab Aelita as you go by!
Where are you taking me?
I have no idea.
There’s an interface!
I can get in.
Incredible!
What?
It’s unbelieveable.
The interface gives access…
to XANA’s own data!
Huh?
Sector five is where XANA lives!
XANA’s not a very good housekeeper.
There’s some weird things
hanging around this place.
I’ve got access to all kinds of data. It’s crazy!
Look for the specific
devirtualization code for sector five.
If you find it, we can
rescue Odd and Ulrich!
Jeremie, I’m gonna need the Overwing.
Uh-oh. Bad news.
When Aelita’s working on the interface,
I can’t do anything from my end.
I think I found it. I’m transmitting it to you.
Okay. I’m taking over again now.
What would a nice girl like Yumi doing here?
Where are we, anyway?
Jeremie, the Overwing! Now!
It’s on the way!
How do we get out of here?
There are some tunnels.
They’re closed!
Lets see.
Tunnels…
What if…
What if they corresponded to those
that open onto the arena?
Yippie! It works!
Nice one, Einstein!
Yumi!
Jeremie, I got out through a way tower!
Okay. Now get to a neutral tower.
I’ll bring you in!
Okay. I’m ready, Aelita.
Code: Earth.
It's okay, Jeremie. I’m here.
But what about the others?
I’m entering the new code!
Materialization Yumi!
Materialization Odd!
Materialization Ulrich!
Now all we can do is hope.
Yeah!
We did it!
Odd!
How you feel? Say something!
Something!
Kiwi!
Yumi? What are you doing here?
I believe you all have
some explaining to do.
Hey!
Ah ha!
Trying to outsmart me, huh?
What the…
Belpois!
W-What?
What is this place?
Nothing rings a bell, Jim?
Funny 'cause you’ve
been here before.
What are you talking about?
I don’t remember this!
Well, yes and no.
Huh?
Return to the past now.
So, then. You still refuse
to give us an explanation?
Alright, I’ll tell you.
I’m in love.
Ah, Yumi, I knew there was a reason.
And would you tell us
your boyfriend’s name?
No. Sorry, I won’t mom.
See you tonight.
Ugh!
Well, that sure seemed to
satisfy your parents.
What did you tell them?
The truth.
CLOSED CAPTIONING PROVIDED BY
REDDIT.COM/R/CODELYOKO